Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
MAN 1:
There have been shots fired.
MAN 2: Total civil unrest
is happening throughout
the Los Angeles area.
WOMAN 1: Dozens of police
are running down the streets.
MAN 3: Smoke reigned
over the entire city.
WOMAN 1: We're telling
anybody who's in downtown
South Central...
MAN 4: There are 38 dead
and more than...
MAN 5: The EMT are having
a hard time getting in...
MAN 6: where truck driver
Reginald Denny was pulled
from his vehicle...
WOMAN 2: The city resembles
a war zone.
MAN 7: Crowds gathered
at Parker Center downtown.
MAN 8: here in Hollywood.
where looters have
struck many businesses.
WOMAN 2: There have been
3.600 structural fires.
Thick. black smoke rising
from the countless fires
in Hollywood.
downtown. Compton.
Watts and Long Beach...
(HELICOPTER ROTOR WHIRRING)
EVA: In America.
a girl can be crowned a princess
for her beauty and her grace.
But an Aztec princess
is chosen for her blood...
MR. BENITEZ: Eva?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
to fight for her people.
as Papi and his father fought
against those who say
we are less than they are.
who say we are
not equal in beauty
and in blessings.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
It was the first day of school.
and I was waiting
for my father
to take me to the bus.
Roberto!
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(GUN FIRING)
MR. BENITEZ: Eva!
And I saw the war
for the first time.
Eva! Eva!
POLICEMAN: Police! Open up!
They took my father
for retaliation.
He was innocent.
but they took him.
because he was respected
by my people.
They called my people
a gang because we fight
for our America.
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
POLICEMAN: On your feet!
(GRUNTING)
When I got my initiation
into the gang life.
I became third generation.
They beat you
so you won't break.
They are my family.
In Long Beach.
it all comes down
to what you look like.
If you're Latino
or Asian or black.
you could get blasted
any time you walk
out your door.
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(LATINO HIP-HOP
PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
(GUNS FIRING)
We fight each other
for territory.
We kill each other over race.
pride and respect.
We fight for what is ours.
(ALL MURMURING)
They think they're winning
by jumping me now.
but soon they're all going down.
War has been declared.
Here's your coffee.
Thank you.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING IN HALL)
Mmm.
I brought my lesson plans.
I'd love it if you'd
look them over.
Yes. and these
are the classes
you'll start with.
Freshman English.
four classes.
about 150 students in all.
Some of them are just
out of juvenile hall.
One or two might be
wearing ankle cuffs
to monitor their whereabouts.
And you see here.
we'll have to revise
your lesson plans.
And if you look
at their scores.
these vocabulary lists
and some of these. uh.
the books. uh.
Homer's The Odyssey.
they're gonna be
too difficult for them.
All right.
Also. for most of them
to get here it takes
three buses.
almost 90 minutes each way.
My God.
So I wouldn't give them
too much of a homework load.
You'll just be wasting
a lot of time following up
on overdue work.
All right.
Thank you.
You're from Newport Beach?
Yes.
It's too bad you weren't here
even two years ago. you know.
We used to have one
of the highest scholastic
records in the district.
but since
voluntary integration
was suggested.
we've. um.
lost over 75%
of our strongest students.
Well. actually.
I chose Wilson because
of the integration program.
I think what's happening
here is really exciting.
don't you?
My father was involved
in the civil rights movement.
And I remember
when I was watching
the LA riots on TV.
I was thinking of going
to law school at the time.
And I thought. "God. by the time
"you're defending a kid
in a courtroom.
the battle's already lost."
I think the real fighting
should happen here
in the classroom.
Well. that's a very. uh.
(TELEPHONES RINGING)
well-thought-out phrase.
Erin.
I think you're a lovely.
intelligent woman.
But you're a first-time teacher.
As head of this department.
I have to be confident
you're capable
of dealing with what
we have to face here.
I am.
I know I have a lot
to learn as a teacher.
but I'm a really good student.
I am. and I really
want to be here.
Those are lovely pearls.
Thank you. From my father.
I wouldn't wear them to class.
(HIP-HOP HOORAY PLAYING)
♪ Hip-hop hooray
Hey. ho
♪ Hey. ho
Honey?
(GROANS)
What?
Do I look like a teacher?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
♪ I'm rockin' and
you're yawning
♪ But you never look my way
♪ I'm lickin' down you darlin'
In every single way
♪ Your funny flow is foreign
And a green card's
on the way
♪ This ain't got shit
to do with shampoo
♪ But watch
your head and shoulder
Hey!
♪ A raid afraid of
what I made of
♪ Plus played a funky fit
so save your flips and tricks
♪ For that music
and the monkey bit
♪ Triggers from
the Grilltown Illtown
♪ Some ask how it feels now
♪ The deal is
that we're real
so we're still around
♪ Don't lamp with
a freestyle phantom
ain't tryin' to be handsome
♪ Shrinkin' what you're
thinkin' cause I'm vampin'
♪ I live and die for hip hop
♪ This is hip hop for today
♪ I give props to hip hop
so hip-hop hooray
♪ Hey. ho
♪ Hip-hop hooray
Hey. ho
♪ Hey. ho ♪
(BELL RINGING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
GIRL: Hey. Chris.
yo. what up?
(BELL RINGING)
Hello.
Hey. yo.
let's sit right here. man.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Hi.
Hey. girl. you wanna give me
some fries with that shake?
(LAUGHING)
My name is Erin Gruwell.
Welcome to Freshman English.
JAMAL:
I give this bitch a week.
Hi.
Um. okay. Brandy Ross?
Gloria Munez.
ERIN: Alejandro Santiago.
Andre Bryant.
Eva Benitez.
Eva. not Eva.
Eva.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Okay. make sure
that you take a...
Yeah. I know.
Uh. Ben Samuels?
MARCUS:
That white boy hoping
he's in the wrong room.
BEN:
I gotta get out of here.
Sindy Ngor.
Right here.
Is that correct?
Jamal Hill?
Man. what am I doing in here?
This whole ghetto-ass class
has got people in here
looking like a bad rerun
of Cops and shit.
You know what I'm saying?
It's true.
Are you Jamal?
Yeah.
Well. for some reason
they have you registered
in this class.
Yeah. and that's some bullshit.
It's the dumb class. coz.
It means you're too dumb.
Man. say it to my face. coz.
I just did.
See what I mean? Dumb.
Man. I know you
ain't talking to me!
Um. okay...
Look. homey.
I'll beat that ass. homeboy.
Can you please sit back down?
Look. I got your spot
on the team.
That's why you're over there
wagging your tongue.
Please sit back in your seats.
Look. your spot is good as gone.
I don't know why you keep
wasting your time
coming to practice
with them two-year-old
Nikes on your feet!
You don't know
nothing about me. coz!
ANDRE: Broke down
my whole situation.
Jamal?
So. now you're in
my face now. right?
Sit your punk ass down!
Sit your punk ass down.
homeboy!
I will run that ass
off the field.
Shut your ass up.
What's up. homey?
I mean. what's up?
JAMAL:
Sit your ass down. homey!
Excuse me.
may I please get
some help in here?
So do something!
Back up!
You touching me now?
Sit down. homeboy.
Back up. I'm not gonna
tell you again.
You gonna look
at my face now. right?
You ain't taking nothing
from me. homeboy!
I will run
your ass off the field!
Boy. sit your ass back down.
Don't even worry about it.
I'm gonna see you.
Tell him.
Sit his ass down.
Sit your ass down.
Thank you.
Let him out of here. man.
That's some bullshit.
MARGARET: Erin?
Erin. this is Brian Gelford.
He teaches Junior English
and the Distinguished
Honors Classes.
Hi. Erin Gruwell.
Nice to meet you.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
You saw a little
action today. I hear.
Oh. yeah.
It happened so fast.
Well. don't be discouraged.
You put your time in.
in a few years.
you'll be able to teach juniors.
They're a pleasure.
By then. most of your kids
will be gone anyway.
What do you mean?
Well. eventually.
they just stop coming.
Well. if I do my job.
they might be
lining up at the door.
Right?
Yeah.
Nice pearls.
Thank you.
EVA: If it was up to me.
I wouldn't even be in school.
My probation officer
threatened me.
telling me
it was either school
or boot camp.
Dumbass.
He thinks that the problems
going on in Long Beach
aren't going to
touch me at Wilson.
My PO doesn't understand
that schools
are like the city.
and the city
is just like a prison.
all of them divided
into separate sections.
depending on tribes.
There's Little Cambodia.
The Ghetto.
Wonder Bread Land.
And us.
South of the Border
or Little Tijuana.
That's just the way it is.
and everyone knows it.
But soon enough.
you have little wannabes
trying to hit you up at school.
demanding respect
they haven't earned.
It looks like this.
one tribe drifting quietly
to another's territory
without respect.
as if to claim
what isn't theirs.
An outsider looking in
would never see it.
but we could feel it.
Something was coming.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
ERIN: Settle down.
Let's go over the first name
on the list. Homer.
Homer's The Odyssey.
I know Homer the Simpson.
(ALL LAUGHING)
No. this Homer
was an ancient Greek.
but maybe he was bald
just like Homer Simpson.
(STUDENTS SCOFFING)
Okay.
What's up?
Quietly. please.
Mrs. Gruwell.
he just took my damn bag!
Shut up!
Ain't nobody touched
your damn bag.
Yeah. I saw you.
Jamal. Jamal.
Get her backpack.
I didn't do nothing anyway!
Jamal. Jamal.
Okay.
(GIRL SCREAMING)
(ALARM BELL RINGING)
(STUDENTS CLAMOURING)
Wait! Wait!
Please. stay in your seats!
Wait! Stay in
your seats! Please!
(BELL CONTINUES RINGING)
Slanty-eyed bitch!
BANNING:
Return to your classrooms.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Return to the classrooms
immediately.
That's all you got?
Clear the school lawn
and the recreation field now!
Classrooms.
or you will be subject
to disciplinary action.
You can best help yourself
and your fellow students
and your school by returning
to your classrooms now.
Please return
to your classrooms.
Get up. bitch!
All students must return
to their classrooms
immediately.
SCOTT: Erin?
Erin.
Hey. baby.
You okay?
Come here.
Are you sure about this?
Well. it's not exactly
how I pictured it.
Don't tell my dad.
Hopefully. he hasn't
seen the news.
So. how's work?
Dad.
I was asking your husband.
It's good.
I mean. for now.
It's a good company.
I pretty much run
the computer data
department.
I thought you were an architect.
He is.
He's just
taking a break.
And the money's good for now.
How much are you making.
$27.000 before taxes?
If you know. why are you asking?
So. what's everybody gonna eat?
With your brains.
you could run
a major corporation.
Instead. I worry all night
because you're a teacher
at Attica.
Can you hear what you're saying?
How many times
have I listened to you
about walking
civil rights marches?
These gangs are criminals.
not activists.
You read the papers?
They said the same thing
about the Black Panthers.
I'll lay odds
your kids don't even know
who Rap Brown
or Eldridge Cleaver were.
You're gonna waste
your talents on people
who don't give a damn
about education.
It breaks my heart.
I tell you the truth.
Well...
I'm sorry.
I can't help that.
You think this is
good enough for her?
Yeah. I do.
Look. Steve.
if Erin thinks
she can teach these kids.
she can.
You telling her she can't
is just gonna make her mad.
So he doesn't like your job.
So what?
Why do you let it get to you?
I don't know. it just does.
I'm not used to
disappointing him. I...
Just let me know
when I can brush
my teeth.
I hate that we don't
have our own sinks.
Come in. There's room.
All right. Thank you.
I can't believe
he brought up my salary.
What's happened to him?
He was like
Atticus Finch to me
when I was growing up.
and now he's talking
about salaries?
I think he's playing
too much golf.
In fact. I think
he needs an intervention.
(CHUCKLES)
Why isn't being a teacher
good enough for him?
Honey. just calm down.
You know.
except for marrying me.
you never seriously
disappoint him.
He worships you.
He likes you.
He just doesn't...
He just doesn't think
I'm good enough for you.
which is fine.
That's what fathers do.
I'm sure I'll be that way
someday.
Look. just. you know.
stop worrying about being
his perfect daughter.
You don't live in his house.
you live in ours.
Or until we find one.
Or until you build us one.
Yeah.
With extra sinks.
You're a teacher
because you say you are.
(KEEP YA HEAD UP BY 2PAC
PLAYING ON BOOMBOX)
♪ Little somethin'
for my godson Elijah
♪ And a little girl
named Corinne
♪ Some say
the blacker the berry.
the sweeter the juice
♪ I say the darker the flesh
I have this idea.
We're gonna be covering poetry.
Who here likes Tupac Shakur?
It's 2Pac.
2Pac Shakur. Excuse me.
Raise your hand.
Really?
(SHUTS OFF BOOMBOX)
I thought
there'd be more fans.
I have the lyrics
to this song printed out.
I want you
to listen to this phrase
I have up on the board.
It's an example
of an internal rhyme.
What he does
is very sophisticated
and cool. actually.
"Man-child
in the promised land
couldn't afford many heroes
"Moms was the only one there
Pops was a no-show
"And. no.
I guess you didn't know
"that I would grow
to be so strong
"You looking kinda pale.
was it the ale?
Oh. pops was wrong
"Where was the money
that you said
you would send me?
"Talked on the phone
and you sounded so friendly"
Think we don't know 2Pac?
White girl
gonna teach us about rap.
No. it's not that.
See. what I was trying
to do...
You have no idea
what you're doing
up there. do you?
You ever been a teacher before?
(JAMAL EXCLAIMING)
And teacher gets nailed. y'all!
All right. Jamal. enough.
Jamal! That's enough!
You know what?
I want you to move
to this front seat
right here now.
What?
Come on.
I am sick of these antics
in my classroom.
Well. there you are.
I was wondering
when you were gonna
lose that damn smile.
Switch with Ben.
Come on.
I can't go back there alone.
It'll be fine.
No. it won't.
I'm not sitting near him.
I ain't going up
there without my homey.
I'm not sitting
back there alone!
All right.
Shut up.
All right. you know what?
I want you all to move
to this side of the room.
You in the back. up here.
Sindy and all of you.
move to the back.
Come on. Let's go. Now!
Get your ass back to China.
all of y'all.
You're all little
midget-ass punks.
Move before
I stomp your peanuts.
Boo!
Get your ass to the back. boy.
(CODE OF THE STREETS
BY GANG STARR PLAYING)
♪ It starts
with the young ones
doing crime for fun
♪ And if you ain't down.
you'll get played out. son
♪ So let's get a car.
you know. a fly whip
♪ Get a dent.
pull a screwdriver.
and be off quick
♪ With a dope ride.
yeah. and a rowdy crew
♪ We can bag us a Benz
and an Audi. too
♪ Even a jeep or a van.
goddamn.
we're getting ours. yo
♪ Take a trip up the strip
and be like stars so
Get off my desk.
♪ They can't do jack.
that's why
a young brother's open
♪ To do anything.
anywhere. anyplace
♪ Buckwild
in another court case
♪ It's the code
of the streets
So. everybody happy
with the new borders?
♪ They might say
we're a menace to society
♪ But at the same time I say
"Why is it me?"
♪ Am I the target.
for destruction ♪
Eva?
Where are you going?
Hey! Hey!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
(BELL RINGING)
(BABY WAILING)
(REBIRTH OF SLICK BY DIGABLE
PLANETS PLAYING ON BOOMBOX)
♪ We like the breeze
flow straight out of our lids
♪ Them they got moved
by these hard rock
Brooklyn kids
♪ Us flow a rush
when the DJ's boomin' classics
♪ You dig the crew
on the fattest
hip hop records
♪ The puba of the styles
like Miles and shit
♪ Like sixties funky worms
with waves and perms
♪ Just sendin' chunky rhythms
right down your block
♪ We be to rap
what key be to lock
♪ But I'm cool like dat
I'm cool like dat
♪ I'm cool like dat
I'm cool. I'm cool
♪ We be the chocolates taps
on my raps
♪ She innovates
after sweeter cat naps
♪ He at the funk club
with the vibrate
♪ Them they be crazy down
with the five plate
♪ It can kick a plan
then a crowd burst
♪ Me I be diggin' it
with the bump verse
♪ Us we be freakin'
till dawn blinks an eye
♪ He gives the strangest
smile so I say hi
♪ Who understood
yeah understood the plan
♪ Him heard a beat
and put it to his hands
♪ What I just flip
let borders get loose
♪ How to consume
or they'll be just like juice
♪ If it's the shit
we'll lift it off the plastic
♪ The babes'll go spastic
Hip hop gains a classic
♪ Pimp playin' shock
it don't matter I'm fatter
♪ Ask Butta how I zone
♪ Man Cleopatra Jones
♪ And I'm chill like dat
♪ I'm chill like dat
I'm chill like dat
I'm chill. I'm chill
This is bull!
Come on. man! What the...
What the hell? Damn!
I want my money back!
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
This shit took my damn money!
I want my damn money back!
Look what you
putting me through. Shit!
Learn to speak
the damn language!
You're from this country.
aren't you?
I want my money back!
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
♪ I'm peace like dat
I'm peace like dat
♪ Hey check it out man
I groove like dat
♪ I'm smooth like dat
♪ We jazz like dat
♪ We freak like dat
We zoom like dat
We out. we out ♪
(GUN FIRING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Come on! Let's go!
Come on. come on. girl!
Let's go!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
EVA: Paco was scared.
In the car. he said.
"You can't go against
your own people.
your own blood."
The same words
my father used so many times.
Only I saw Paco.
The others were turned away.
So when the police
questioned me.
I knew I had to protect him.
All right. everyone.
we need to get started
so classes won't be too delayed.
Principal Banning
would like to say something
in the light
of last night's events.
I've spoken to the police.
As you might already know.
there were persons involved
in last night's shooting
who are Wilson students.
Grant Rice has been arrested
as a prime suspect.
Ms. Gruwell.
apparently one
of your students.
Eva Benitez...
Eva.
Has identified
him as the shooter.
She's the prime witness
in the case.
It is our policy
not to discuss the subject
inside the classroom.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Hey. Tiny. check this out.
Hey. Hey!
Yes?
(GIGGLING)
All right.
Um. Gloria?
Please read
the first sentence
on the board.
Why me?
Because I know
how much you love to read.
Close the magazine.
"Odysseus had
no sense of direction."
ERIN: Now. none of these
sentences are correct.
I'd like you
to rewrite these sentences
using the proper tenses
and spelling on page four
of your workbooks.
(GIGGLING)
BRANDY: Um.
I don't have a page four.
It got torn out.
ERIN: Okay.
why don't you just use
the next blank page?
(ALL GIGGLING)
What's going on?
What is that?
Give it to me.
What is this?
Just leave it alone.
You think this is funny?
Tito?
Would this be funny
if it were a picture of you?
It ain't.
Close the workbooks.
Maybe we should talk about art.
Tito's got real talent.
don't you think?
ALL: Yeah. yeah.
BOY: Go. Tito.
You know something?
I saw a picture
just like this once
in a museum.
Only it wasn't a black man.
it was a Jewish man.
And instead of the big lips.
he had a really big nose.
like a rat's nose.
But he wasn't just
one particular Jewish man.
this was a drawing of all Jews.
And these drawings
were put in the newspapers
by the most famous gang
in history.
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
That's us. dawg.
Mmm.
You think you know
all about gangs?
You're amateurs.
This gang would
put you all to shame.
And they started
out poor and angry.
and everybody
looked down on them.
Until one man decided
to give them some pride.
an identity
and somebody to blame.
You take over neighborhoods?
That's nothing compared to them.
They took over countries.
And you wanna know how?
They just wiped out
everybody else.
ALL: Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. they wiped out
everybody they didn't like.
and everybody they blamed
for their life being hard.
And one of the ways
they did it
was by doing this.
See. they'd print pictures
like this in the newspapers.
Jewish people
with big. long noses.
Blacks with big. fat lips.
They'd also publish
scientific evidence
that proved Jews and blacks
were the lowest form
of human species.
Jews and blacks
were more like animals.
And because
they were just like animals
it didn't really matter
whether they lived or died.
In fact. life would be
a whole lot better
if they were all dead.
That's how a holocaust happens.
And that's what you all
think of each other.
You don't know nothing.
homegirl.
No. I don't. Marcus!
So why don't you
explain it to me?
I ain't explaining shit to you!
(ALL CHATTERING)
Do you even know how we live?
We was here first. man.
Just shut that shit up. homeboy.
All right!
All right! All right!
So what you're saying is.
if the Latinos weren't here.
or the Cambodians or the blacks
or the whites
or whoever they are.
if they weren't here.
everything would be
better for you.
isn't that right?
BOY: Of course
it'd be better!
It'd be better
if you weren't here.
Right. Right.
It starts with
a drawing like this.
and then some kid
dies in a drive-by.
never even knowing what hit him.
You don't know nothing!
You don't know the pain we feel.
You don't know
what we got to do.
You got no respect
for how we living.
You got us in here.
teaching us
this grammar shit.
and then we got to
go out there again.
And what are you telling me
about that. huh?
What are you doing in here
that makes a goddamn
difference to my life?
You don't feel respected.
Is that what you're saying. Eva?
Well. maybe you're not.
But to get respect.
you have to give it.
That's bullshit.
What?
Why should I give
my respect to you?
'Cause you're a teacher?
I don't know you.
How do I know
you're not a liar
standing up there?
How do I know
you're not a bad person
standing up there?
I'm not just gonna
give you my respect
because you're called a teacher.
White people always
wanting their respect
like they deserve it for free.
I'm a teacher.
It doesn't matter
what color I am.
It's all about color.
It's about people deciding
what you deserve.
about people wanting
what they don't deserve.
about whites thinking
they run this world
no matter what.
You see. I hate white people.
You hate me?
Yeah.
You don't know me.
I know what you can do.
I saw white cops
shoot my friend in the back
for reaching into his pocket!
His pocket.
I saw white cops
break into my house
and take my father for no reason
except because
they feel like it!
Except because they can.
And they can
because they're white.
So I hate white people on sight!
Ben. do you have
anything to say?
Can I please get out of here?
Lady. stop acting
like you're trying
to understand our situation
and just do your little
babysitting up there.
That's all you think this is?
It ain't nothing else.
When I look out in the world.
I don't see nobody
that looks like me
with their pockets full.
unless they're rapping
a lyric or dribbling a ball.
So what else you got
in here for me?
And what if you can't rap
a lyric or dribble a ball?
It ain't this.
I know that much.
Damn right.
And you all think
you're gonna make it
to graduation like this?
I made it to high school.
Ain't nobody stopped me.
Lady. I'm lucky
if I make it to 18.
We in a war.
We're graduating
every day we live.
because we ain't afraid
to die protecting our own.
At least when you die
for your own.
you die with respect.
you die a warrior.
That's right.
So when you're dead.
you'll get respect?
Is that what you think?
BOY 1: That's right.
BOY 2: That's right.
Yeah.
BOY 3: Yeah.
You know what's gonna happen
when you die?
You're gonna rot in the ground.
And people are gonna
go on living.
and they're gonna
forget all about you.
And when you rot.
do you think it's gonna matter
whether you were
an original gangster?
You're dead.
And nobody. nobody
is gonna wanna remember you.
because all you left behind
in this world is this.
You're raising your hand?
That thing
that you said before.
the Holocause?
Holocaust. yes.
What is that?
Raise your hand if you know
what the Holocaust is.
Raise your hand
if anyone in this classroom
has ever been shot at.
(BELL RINGING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
What about this?
We were discussing
the Holocaust.
No. they won't be able
to read that.
We can try.
The books are just
sitting here.
Look at their reading scores.
And if I give your kids
these books.
I'll never see them again.
If I do. they'll be damaged.
What about these?
Romeo and Juliet.
That's a great gang story.
No. not the books.
This is what we give them.
It is Romeo and Juliet.
but it's a condensed version.
But even these.
look how they treat them.
See how torn up they are?
They draw on them.
Ms. Campbell?
They know they get these
because no one thinks
they're smart enough
for real books.
Well. I don't have
the budget to buy
new books every semester
when these kids
don't return them.
So. what do I do?
Buy their books myself?
Well. that's up to you.
but you'd be wasting
your money.
Is there someone else
I can speak to about this?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry. but
I don't understand.
Does the Long Beach
Board of Ed agree
that these books
should just sit here
and not be used at all?
Let me explain.
It's called
site-based instruction.
It means that I
and the principal
each have the authority
to make these kinds
of decisions without having
to go to the Board.
who have bigger problems
to solve.
Do you understand
how it works now?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to overstep
your authority.
I would never do that.
I just...
I don't know how to make them
interested in reading
with these.
You can't make someone
want an education.
The best you can do
is try to get them to obey.
to learn discipline.
That would be a tremendous
accomplishment for them.
Since you know Margaret
better than I do.
if I could just get
some backup from you.
I really think
that the stories like
The Diary of Anne Frank and...
That they'd be
so great for them.
and she doesn't seem
to understand
that they could relate
to these stories
considering all that they face.
Oh. of course.
It's a universal story.
I mean. Anne Frank. Rodney King.
they're almost interchangeable.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Are you making fun of me?
Yeah.
God. listen
to what you're saying.
How dare you compare them
to Anne Frank?
They don't hide.
They drive around in the open
with automatic weapons.
I'm the one living in fear.
I can't walk out
my door at night.
And you blame these kids?
This was an A-list school
before they came here.
And look what
they turned it into.
I mean. does it make sense
that kids who want
an education should suffer
because their high school
gets turned into
a reform school?
Because kids
who don't want to be here.
and shouldn't be here.
are forced to be here
by the geniuses
running the school district?
Integration's a lie.
Oh. yeah. we teachers.
we can't say that
or we lose our jobs
for being racist.
So. please.
stop your cheerleading. Erin.
You're ridiculous.
You don't know
the first thing
about these kids.
And you're not qualified
to make judgments
about the teachers
who have to survive this place.
(CLEARING THROAT)
(LISTEN
BY TALIB KWELI PLAYING)
♪ Listen
♪ Listen. listen
♪ There's something
I want to tell you
♪ Wake up. wake up.
wake up a minute
♪ Listen
♪ Wake up. wake up.
wake up a minute
wake up a minute ♪
We're gonna play a game.
all right?
It's a lot of fun. I promise.
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
Look. you can either
sit in your seats reading
those workbooks.
or you can play a game.
Either way.
you're in here
till the bell rings.
Okay. This is called
the Line Game.
I'm gonna ask you a question.
If that question
applies to you.
you step onto the line.
and then step back away
for the next question.
Easy. right?
GIRL: Yeah. whatever.
The first question.
how many of you have
the new Snoop Dogg album?
(ALL CHATTERING)
Did you steal it?
ERIN: Okay. back away.
Next question.
how many of you have seen
Boyz n the Hood?
(ALL CHATTERING)
Okay. Next question.
How many of you
live in the projects?
How many of you know someone.
a friend or relative.
who was or is
in juvenile hall or jail?
How many of you have been
in juvenile hall or jail
for any length of time?
BOY: Detention don't count.
(BOY CHUCKLING)
Does a refugee camp count?
You decide.
How many of you know
where to get drugs right now?
How many of you
know someone in a gang?
are gang members?
GIRL 1: Nice try.
GIRL 2: Nice try.
Okay. that was
a stupid question.
wasn't it?
Yeah.
You're not allowed
gang affiliations in school.
I apologize for asking.
My badness.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Okay. now I'm gonna ask you
a more serious question.
Stand on the line
if you've lost a friend
to gang violence.
Stay on the line
if you've lost
more than one friend.
Three.
Four or more.
Okay.
I'd like us to pay respect
to those people now.
Wherever you are.
just speak their name.
(STUDENTS WHISPERING)
James.
Beatriz.
Thank you all very much.
Now. I have something
for each of you.
Everyone has their own story.
and it's important for you
to tell your own story.
even to yourself.
So. what we're going to do is
we're gonna write every day
in these journals.
You can write about
whatever you want.
the past.
the present. the future.
You can write
it like a diary.
or you can write
songs. poems. any good thing.
bad thing. anything.
But you have to write every day.
Keep a pen nearby.
Whenever you feel
the inspiration.
And they won't be graded.
How can I give an A or a B
for writing the truth. right?
And I will not read them
unless you give me
permission.
I will need to see
that you've made an entry.
but I'll... I'll just do this.
skim to see
that you wrote that day.
Now. if you want me
to read it. I have...
Excuse me.
A cabinet over here.
It has a lock on it.
I will keep it
open during class.
and you can leave
your diary there
if you want me to read it.
I will lock this cabinet
at the end of every class.
Okay?
So. you can each come up.
one by one.
and take your own journal.
Whenever you're ready.
ERIN: Eva holds back.
but I know she
wants to be involved.
She's so stubborn.
Who really surprised me
was Brandy.
who never says a word.
but she was the first
to step up and take
a journal. I...
Honey. here. Here. sit down.
It's all right.
No. it's all right.
I'll move this.
I don't mind standing.
Food goes straight down.
How much longer
are you gonna be?
I don't know.
Want to help?
Not really.
I'm a terrible drawer.
You're an architect.
Hmm. All right.
I... I just don't want to.
What's the matter?
Is something wrong?
No. it's nothing.
Well. it's just. you know.
I want to hear all this.
I do.
It just...
I feel like we haven't
talked about anything.
other than your job.
in like forever.
I'm sorry. Well.
what's going on at work?
Nothing.
I don't want to talk
about that. either.
I just want to hang out.
I want to be home.
And I want to be
with my schoolteacher.
I've always had this fantasy
about being kept
late after school.
Well. I'm sorry I left
my dirty erasers at work.
Do all the other teachers
put in this much
extra effort?
I don't know.
I'm kind of making it up
as I go along.
And the other teachers
don't really talk to me.
I mean. Brian and Margaret...
Honey.
I don't want to think.
I'm sorry.
Okay. don't think.
I just wanna...
I'm almost done. okay?
So. how much longer?
Not long. Promise.
BRIAN: Thank you so much
for coming. Susan's a terrific
student. Thank you.
Great to see you.
Good night. Take care.
Jim. thank you so much.
Thanks. Brian.
I appreciate you guys coming
to Parents' Night.
Drive safe.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(KEYS JINGLING)
BRANDY: In every war.
there is an enemy.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I watched my mother
being half beaten to death
and watched
as blood and tears
streamed down her face.
I felt useless and scared
and furious at the same time.
Stay there. Brandy.
Watch the kids!
Get my money!
I can still feel
the sting of the belt
on my back and my legs.
One time.
he couldn't pay the rent.
And that night
he stopped us on the street
and pointed to the concrete.
He said. "Pick a spot."
MARCUS: Clive was my boy.
He had my back plenty of times.
We was like one fist.
me and him. one army.
That's heavy.
Yeah.
That's the real shit right here.
Nobody'll jump us now.
But we got to practice
'cause this. this got power.
You shoot it. it...
(GUN FIRES)
I sat there
till the police came.
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
But when they come.
all they see is a dead body.
a gun and a nigga.
They took me to juvenile hall.
First night was the scariest.
(BOYS SCREAMING)
Inmates banging on the walls.
throwing up their gang signs.
yelling out who they were.
where they're from.
I cried my first night.
Can't never let
nobody know that.
I spent the next few years
in and out of cells.
Every day I'd worry.
"When will I be free?"
My brother taught me
what the life is
for a young black man.
Do what you have to.
pimp. deal. whatever.
Learn what colors to learn.
gang boundaries.
You can stay on one corner.
you can't stay on another.
ANDRE: Learn to be quiet.
A wrong word can get you popped.
If you look in my eyes.
you'll see a loving girl.
If you look at my smile.
you'll see nothing wrong.
GLORIA:
If you pull up my shirt.
you'll see the bruises.
What did I do
to make him so mad?
JAMAL: At 16.
I've seen more dead bodies
than a mortician.
Every time I step out my door.
I'm faced with the risk
of being shot.
To the outside world.
it's just another dead body
on the street corner.
They don't know
that he was my friend.
SINDY:
During the war in Cambodia.
the camp stripped away
my father's dignity.
He sometimes tries
to hurt my mom and me.
I feel like I have to
protect my family.
I was having trouble
deciding what candy
I wanted.
then I heard gunshots.
I looked down to see
that one of my friends
had blood coming out
of his back and his mouth.
The next day.
I pulled up my shirt
and got strapped with a gun
I found in an alley by my house.
EVA: I don't even know
how this war started.
It's just two sides
who tripped each other
way back.
Who cares about
the history behind it?
I am my father's daughter.
And when they call me
to testify.
I will protect
my own no matter what.
TITO: Nobody cares what I do.
Why should I bother
coming to school?
MARCUS: My friends
are soldiers. not of war.
but of the streets.
They fight for their lives.
ALEJANDRO: I hate
the cold feeling of a gun
against my skin.
It makes me shiver.
It's a crazy-ass life.
Once you're in.
there's no getting out.
MARCUS:
Every time I jump somebody in
and make someone
a part of our gang.
it's another baptism.
They give us their life.
we give them a new one.
I've lost many friends
who have died
in an undeclared war.
To the soldiers and me.
it's all worth it.
Risk your life
dodging bullets.
pulling triggers.
It's all worth it.
Rum and Coke.
Oh. man.
This is...
Mr. Gruwell?
Your table is ready.
Follow me.
Dad. I got them.
Okay.
Dad. I don't know
what to do with this.
I'm not a social worker.
I'm barely a teacher.
Thank you.
These kids.
they're 14. 15 years old.
and if they make it
through the day alive.
that's good enough.
And I'm supposed to teach them?
Listen to me.
You're not responsible
for their lives
outside that classroom.
Just do your job
the best you can.
How?
The administration
doesn't give me
any resources.
no books. no support.
So. what should I do?
Fulfill your obligation
till the end
of the school year.
but line up another position.
Success follows experience.
So. get some more experience.
But no matter what.
you gotta remember.
it's just a job.
If you're not right
for this one.
get another job.
You're gonna sell bras
at a department store?
Just part-time.
I'm having a little trouble
getting books and things
for the kids.
So. a little extra money
will give me
a little more freedom
to do what I want.
And this way
you can play tennis
with Evan after work.
Okay. let me
get my head around this.
You're going to get
an extra job
to pay for your job.
It's just temporary.
I promise.
Once the kids' grades go up.
I'll get a little more help
from the school.
And I get
an employee's discount.
Isn't that great?
Want a new TV?
Yeah.
Um. excuse me.
if I wanted to order
any books in bulk.
could I get
some sort of a discount?
These books are brand new.
I know.
Okay. guys. gals.
Listen up.
The only problem
with this book is
it's about a gang member
and there's violence in it.
so you may not be able
to read it as part
of the curriculum.
So. I'm going to try my best
to get permission. all right?
It's been a little difficult
getting their attention.
Up until recently.
the only thing they hated
more than each other was me.
Well. you united them
and that's a step.
What can I do for you?
I want to do more with them.
and I need the support
of someone in power.
You have to take this up
with your department head
and your principal.
I can't get involved
in inner school policy.
My principal only listens
to my department head.
and she's not very supportive.
You'll have to find a way
to deal with it.
No. I'd rather
just deal directly
with someone in power.
Ms. Gruwell.
there's a system in place
based on years of running
an educational facility.
You have to follow that system.
No. I won't.
(PHONES RINGING)
Look. I'm just trying
to do my job here.
What's the point
of a voluntary
integration program
if the kids making
it to high school
have a 5th grade reading level?
I enforced that program.
With all due respect.
all that program is doing
is warehousing these kids
until they're old enough
to disappear.
Look. I appreciate
your intentions.
but there's nothing I can do
on a class-by-class basis.
Dr. Cohn.
why should they waste
their time showing up
when they know
we're wasting our time
teaching them?
We tell them. "Go to school.
Get an education."
And then we say.
"Well. they can't learn.
"so let's not
waste resources."
I'm thinking trips.
Most of them have never
been outside of Long Beach.
They haven't been given
the opportunity
to expand their thinking
about what's out there
for them.
And they're hungry for it.
I know it.
And it's purely a reward system.
They won't get anything
they haven't earned
by doing their work
and upping their grades.
But if Ms. Campbell
won't give you books
because of budget restrictions.
she's not gonna approve
school trips.
I'll raise the money.
I just need to know
I won't meet resistance.
See. I can't promise
them anything
I can't deliver.
It only proves
what they already believe.
All I'm saying is.
Ms. Campbell doesn't need
to be bothered.
(CHUCKLES)
You're a concierge
at the Marriott?
It's just weekends.
You play tennis
with Evan on Saturdays.
And you can play golf
with my dad on Sundays.
Oh. you want me to play golf?
And the bonus is
I get employee rates
on Marriott hotel rooms
all over the world.
I've heard a lot of hyphenates.
but a bra-selling-
English-teacher-
hotel-concierge
has gotta be a new one.
You told me
your part-time job
was temporary.
It is.
I just don't know
for how long.
What if I said no?
No. what?
No. I don't want you
working three jobs.
But I can make
it work. Scott.
No. that's not the point.
You can do anything!
We know that already.
It's just that I... You...
You didn't even ask me.
I'm just trying
to do my job. Scott.
By getting two more jobs?
I don't understand. Erin.
Scott. this is our time
to go after what we want.
when we're young.
before we have a family.
Maybe this is
the perfect time for you
to go back to school.
get your architect's degree.
Wouldn't that be great?
What?
Nothing.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
So. I'll call you
with a list of venues.
I've scheduled
a PTA board meeting
for next week.
So. it should be no problem.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
Lovely to see you. Paula.
Good to see you. too.
Hi.
Hello.
Principal Banning
received a call
from Dr. Cohn
at the school board.
Apparently you're taking
your students on a trip?
Yes. but it's over the weekend.
so it won't affect
any test schedules.
I know how busy you are.
and since
I'm paying for it myself.
I didn't want to bother you.
(OFFICER
BY THE PHARCYDE PLAYING)
♪ I got a letter
from the DMV
♪ The other day
I opened and read it
♪ It said they were suckers ♪
I'll be right back.
Oh. no. No. no. no. Erin?
Get back in the car.
Dad. he lives right here.
I'll get him.
Get back in the car
and lock your door.
What's his name?
Andre Bryant.
Andre.
ANDRE: Since my pop split.
my mom can't even look at me.
'cause I look like my dad.
And with my brother in jail.
she looks at me and thinks
that's where I'm going. too.
She doesn't see me.
She doesn't see me at all.
I'm going out.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
What up?
Hey.
Where you going?
I need you.
No. man. I can't now.
I got something to do.
Tonight. I'll do it tonight.
I gotta go do something.
and I can't carry that
around with me.
(SCOFFS)
Forget it. man.
I'll get somebody else.
I can't be waiting
all day on you.
Hey.
Sorry about your brother. man.
I hear he going away for life.
They won't get it.
The guy he was with
confessed.
To who? Your brother?
Hey. You Andre?
What up?
Hey.
What?
Put on your seat belt.
You. too. young lady.
You kids ever been
to Newport Beach before?
What?
We went there last year
on our way to Paris.
Paris.
(GATE BUZZING)
It's good.
I brought you something.
It's a good book.
I read it in school.
It's about a gang kid.
and I thought you
might like to read it.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He told me what I had to say
when I'm on the stand.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CELL DOOR CLOSING)
ANDRE: At the beginning
of the tour.
they give you a card
with a child's picture on it.
You could find out who they were
and what camp they were sent to.
And at the end of the tour.
you could find out
if they survived.
I got a little girl from Italy.
Tito. your hat.
MAN ON RECORDING:
Kristallnacht.
they called it.
The Night of Broken Glass.
Hundreds of synagogues
looted and burned.
More than 7.000
Jewish stores destroyed.
Over 100 Jews killed.
WOMAN: A small center
for children in Isieux
in the French province of Ain.
Among the children
deported that day
to Birkenau
was 11-year-old
Liliane Berenstein.
who. before leaving.
left behind a letter to God.
ALEJANDRO:
My little boy died.
He got off the train
and they killed him.
I don't know why
it bothered me so much.
I've seen death all my life.
But this little boy
was only five.
JAMAL: Ms. G had a beautiful
dinner for us at the hotel
where she works.
She invited
real Holocaust survivors
from the museum to meet us.
There was Elisabeth Mann.
I had my parents.
my sister. my two brothers.
Gloria Ungar.
If any of you
have seen someone
with a number on their arm.
these were the lucky people.
The people who.
when we came to Auschwitz.
when they tattooed
the people they took us
to do the slave work.
Not the others.
and that included
many of my family.
So. we ran away.
s-some of the young kids.
I was at that time
11-and-a-half years old.
Eddie Ilam.
And where to go. I didn't know.
but I remember one place
where I used to live.
So when I ran there.
there was not one Jew left.
I was in the worst camp.
I was in Auschwitz.
And Renee Firestone.
When I arrived.
my parents were immediately
taken away from me.
My little sister.
who was then 14 years old.
stayed with me
for a little while.
And then later on.
I was separated
from her also.
She lost her whole family
at the camps.
She came to this country
with $4 in her pocket
and a newborn baby.
I'll never forget these people.
MS. FIRESTONE:
And then she was killed
because they didn't want...
I can't believe Ms. G
did all of this for us.
(PHONE RINGING)
(MAN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
(BEEPING)
ERIN: Hi. honey. it's me.
Look. we're still
at the restaurant.
if you wanted to drop by.
We haven't even
ordered dessert yet.
and the kids are having
such an incredible time.
You have to see them.
If you get in soon. come by.
It's only 9:30 now.
(SIGHING)
Okay. I'll see you later.
Love you. Bye.
(KEEP YA HEAD UP
BY 2PAC PLAYING)
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child things
are going to get easier
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child
things'll get brighter
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child things
are going to get easier
♪ Keep your head up
MAN: How many times
I gotta tell your ass again?
Get your butt in here!
♪ Oh. yeah
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child things
are going to get easier
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child
things'll get brighter
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child things
are going to get easier
♪ Keep your head up
♪ Ooh child
things'll get brighter ♪
So. you had all summer
to read and consider
this book.
And you know.
I thought it would be
most valuable
to begin with Victoria
to. uh. give us
the black perspective.
Victoria?
VICTORIA:
Do I have a stamp
on my forehead that says.
"The National Spokesperson
for the Plight
of Black People"?
How the hell should I know
the black perspective on
The Color Purple?
That's it.
if I don't change classes.
I'm gonna hurt this fool.
Teachers treat me
like I'm some kind
of Rosetta stone
for African-Americans.
What? Black people
learn how to read.
and we all miraculously
come to the same conclusion?
At that point. I decided
to check out my friend
Brandy's English class.
Good to see you. man.
Hey. yeah.
How was your summer?
Great.
You're still white. I see.
Okay. everybody. Ready?
Hey. Ms. G.
Hi.
Hi. Ms. G.
(BELL RINGING)
Okay. guys. gals. listen up!
This is what I want you to do.
I want each of you
to step forward
and take one
of these Borders bags.
which contain
the four books we're
gonna read this semester.
(ALL CHEERING)
BOY: All right!
They're very special books.
and they each remind me.
in some way. of each of you.
ALL: Aw.
But. before you take the books.
I want you to take
one of these glasses
of sparkling cider.
and I want each of you
to make a toast.
We're each gonna make
a toast for change.
And what that means is.
from this moment on
every voice that told you
"You can't" is silenced.
Every reason that tells you
things will never change.
disappears.
And the person you were
before this moment.
that person's turn is over.
Now it's your turn.
Okay?
Okay. you ready to get
this party going on?
(ALL GROANING)
What?
Stop doing that. man.
What's the dealio?
Man. I've had boyfriends
since I was. like. 11.
you know.
I believe you.
Shut up.
Okay. well.
I was always the person
that was gonna get pregnant
before I turned 16
and drop out.
Like my mom.
Ain't gonna happen.
Nobody ever listens
to a teenager.
Everybody thinks
you should be happy
just because you're young.
They don't see the wars
that we fight
every single day.
And one day. my war will end.
And I will not die.
And I will not tolerate
abuse from anyone.
I am strong.
My moms kicked me out
when I got jumped into
the gang life.
But I'd like her
to see me graduate.
I'd like to be 18.
Ms. G?
Can I read something
from my diary?
That'd be great.
Who is he?
Man. he's been with us
from freshman year. fool.
What's his name?
I don't know.
"This summer
was the worst summer
in my short 14 years of life.
"It all started
with a phone call.
"My mother was crying
and begging.
"asking for more time
as if she were gasping
for her last breath of air.
"She held me as tight
as she could and cried.
"Her tears hit my shirt
like bullets and told me
"we were being evicted.
"She kept apologizing to me.
"I thought. 'I have no home.
"'I should have asked
for something less expensive
at Christmas.'
"On the morning of the eviction.
"a hard knock
on the door woke me up.
"The sheriff was there
to do his job.
"I looked up at the sky.
waiting for something
to happen.
"My mother
has no family to lean on.
no money coming in.
"Why bother coming to school
or getting good grades
if I'm homeless?
"The bus stops
in front of the school.
"I feel like throwing up.
"I'm wearing clothes
from last year.
"some old shoes
and no new haircut.
"I kept thinking
I'd get laughed at.
"Instead. I'm greeted
by a couple of friends
"who were in
my English class last year.
"And it hits me.
Mrs. Gruwell.
"my crazy English teacher
from last year.
"is the only person
that made me think of hope.
"Talking with friends
about last year's English
and our trips.
"I began to feel better.
"I receive my schedule
and the first teacher
is Mrs. Gruwell in Room 203.
"I walk into the room
and feel as though
"all the problems in life
are not so important anymore.
"I am home."
Yes. you are.
But you're an honors student.
If you transfer
to Ms. Gruwell's class.
think how that will reflect
on your records.
It doesn't matter to me.
My grades
will still be the same.
Look. Ms. Campbell.
When I first transferred
to the school.
I had a 4.0 average.
But when I applied
for advanced placement
at English and Math.
I was told it would be better
for me to be in a class
with my own kind.
Now. when I did get in.
my teacher said.
"Victoria.
it's not every day one finds
an African-American student
"in A.P. and honors courses."
As if I didn't notice.
And when I asked
another honors teacher
why we don't read
more black literature.
she said.
"We don't read
black literature
because of all the sex.
"drugs. cussing
and fornication!"
I thought a simple
"It's inappropriate"
would have sufficed.
Erin can't do that!
Distinguished
Honor Students are mine.
She's not allowed
to teach them.
She's only been here a year.
The student requested it.
And Gruwell has got Cohn
in her back pocket.
What gets me is they're violent.
they break laws.
they destroy school property
and in the end we
make them special.
We reward them like...
I just don't see
what that teaches them.
(T.V. BLARING)
ERIN: Hi!
(MUTES T.V.)
Sorry I'm late.
Did you eat? I'm ordering in.
Are you hungry?
What question do you
want me to answer first?
Did I eat or am I hungry?
I ate. I'm not hungry.
Something really cool
happened today.
I got an honors student.
Congratulations.
Isn't that great?
She actually requested my class.
Can you teach an honors student?
What do you mean?
Well. I mean.
you're used to teaching
your kind of kids.
Can you teach
somebody who's smart?
Of course I can.
Yeah. but it's not
like you have. right?
I mean.
you don't really teach
what everybody else teaches.
My kids' grades are up to B's.
Yeah. but the point is.
that's according to you.
It's not like
they're really learning
what normal kids have to learn.
Normal kids? Yes. they are.
They're reading
The Diary of Anne Frank.
They're learning vocabulary.
grammar. writing. poetry.
All right. Okay.
I apologize. Sorry.
Congratulations.
What is wrong with you?
You know. at Deb's party.
I heard you telling people
that I was an architect
and that my job
was temporary.
I want you to stop that.
all right? I like my job.
Fine.
You're the one who said
you were gonna
be an architect.
Yeah. four years ago.
before we got married.
What. I'm gonna
go back to school now
for two years
and intern for three?
I'll be over 40.
All right. I thought
you still wanted it.
It doesn't matter
if I want it. Erin.
It doesn't mean
it's going to happen.
Why not?
Riting in a diary
is a really strange experience
"for someone like me.
"I mean.
not only because I've never
written anything before.
"but also because
it seems to me that later on.
"neither I nor anyone else
will be interested
"in the musings
of a 13-year-old schoolgirl."
SINDY: "Terrible things
are happening outside.
"At any time of day.
"poor helpless people
are being dragged
out of their homes.
"Families are torn apart."
GLORIA: "If only
I can be myself.
I'll be satisfied.
"I know that I'm a woman
with inner strength
"and a great deal of courage.
"If God lets me live.
I'll achieve more
than Mother ever did."
ANDRE:
"Anti-Jewish decrees
followed in quick succession.
"Jews must wear a yellow star.
"Jews must hand in bicycles.
"Jews are banned from trams
and forbidden to drive."
TITO: "Jews are forbidden
to visit theaters.
"cinemas and other places
of entertainment."
JAMAL:
"Jews may not take part
in public sports.
"Swimming baths.
tennis courts. hockey fields
"and other sports grounds
are all prohibited."
ALEJANDRO: "I can't tell you
how oppressive it is
"never to be able
to go outdoors.
"Also. I'm very afraid
that we will be discovered
and be shot."
EVA: "No one can keep
out of the conflict.
"The entire world is at war.
"And even though the Allies
are doing better.
"the end
is nowhere in sight."
Hi.
When is Anne gonna smoke Hitler?
What?
You know. Take him out?
Eva. this is
The Diary of Anne Frank.
not Die Hard.
Keep reading.
EVA: "We talked about
the most private things.
"but we haven't yet
touched upon the things
closest to my heart.
"I still can't make heads
or tails of Peter.
"Is he superficial?
"Or is it shyness
that holds him back.
even with me?"
(EVA CLEARING THROAT)
Are Anne and Peter
gonna hook up?
I'm not telling you.
EVA: "It's utterly impossible
for me to build my life
on a foundation
"of chaos. suffering and death.
"I see the world being
slowly transformed
into a wilderness.
"I feel the suffering
of millions.
and yet when I look up
at the sky
"I somehow feel
that everything
will change for the better."
Eva. what's wrong?
Why didn't you
tell me she dies?
Why you didn't tell me
she gets caught in the end.
huh?
I hate you and I hate this book.
Eva.
If she dies.
then what about me. huh?
What are you saying about that?
Anne Frank died. but she...
I can't believe they got her!
That ain't supposed to
happen in the story!
That ain't right!
'Cause it's true?
I ain't talking to you!
You're talking around me.
That's the same thing.
See. to me.
she ain't dead at all.
How many friends
did you know that are dead
now that got killed?
Too many to count.
How many have you
read a book about?
Have you seen them on TV
or even in the newspaper?
That's why this story's dope.
She was our age. man.
Anne Frank
understands our situation.
my situation.
And that Miep Gies lady.
the one that helped
hide them?
I like her.
I got all these other books
about her from the library.
Wow. You used
your library card?
No.
(BELL RINGING)
Okay. listen up.
Marcus has given me an idea.
Instead of doing
a book report on
The Diary of Anne Frank.
for our assignment
I want you to write
a letter to Miep Gies.
the woman who helped
shelter the Franks.
She's still alive
and she lives in Europe.
In the letter.
I want you to tell her
how you feel about the book.
Tell her about
your own experiences.
Tell her anything you like.
But I want the letters
to be perfect.
so be prepared to do
more than one draft. okay?
Is she gonna read the letters?
Well. right now
it's a writing assignment.
I'll read them.
We should get her to read them.
Yeah. you can do that.
right. Ms. G?
Well. I don't know.
Maybe we should get her
to come and speak.
Yeah.
and have a big dinner again.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Wait. Guys.
ERIN: Guys! Everyone!
Listen! She's elderly!
I don't know how to contact her.
I don't even know
if she travels.
And it would be
really expensive.
We could raise the money.
Ms. G?
When Miep Gies come.
can I. like.
be the one to escort her in?
(THIS IS HOW WE DO IT
BY MONTELL JORDAN PLAYING)
♪ This is how we do it
♪ La la la la la la la
♪ La la la la la
Five.
♪ This is how we do it
♪ It's Friday night
♪ And I feel all right
♪ The party's here
on the west side
♪ So I reach for my 40
and I turn it up
Hi. I'm trying to get the number
for the Anne Frank Foundation
in Basel. Switzerland.
(PHONE RINGING)
♪ It feels so good
in my hood tonight
♪ The summertime skirts
and the guys in Kani
♪ All the gang bangers
forgot about the drive-by
(ALL CHEERING)
♪ So tip up your cup
and throw your hands up
♪ And let me hear
the party say
♪ I'm kinda buzzed
and it's all because
♪ This is how we do it
♪ South Central
does it like nobody does
♪ This is how we do it
♪ To all my neighbors
you got much flavor
♪ This is how we do it
♪ Let's flip the track.
bring the old school back
♪ This is how we do it
♪ This is how we do it.
all hands are in the air
♪ And wave them
from here to there
♪ If you're an O.G. mack
or a wanna-be player
♪ You see the hood's
been good to me
♪ Ever since
I was a lower-case G
♪ But now I'm a big G.
the girls see I got the money
♪ Hundred dollar bills y'all
♪ If you were from where
I'm from then you would know
♪ That I gotta get mine
in a big black truck
♪ You can get yours in a '64
♪ Whatever it is.
the party's underway
♪ So tip up your cup
and throw your hands up
♪ And let me hear
the party say
BANNING: Come in. Margaret.
♪ This is how we do it
♪ South Central does it
like nobody does
♪ This is how we do it
♪ To all my neighbors
you got much flavor
♪ This is how we do it
♪ Let's flip the track.
bring the old school back
♪ This is how we do it
♪ I'm kinda buzzed.
it's all because
♪ This is how we do it
♪ South Central does it
like nobody does
♪ This is how we do it ♪
(ALL CHEERING)
(PHONE RINGING)
MARCUS: Ms. G sent
our letters all the way
to Amsterdam
to Miep Gies. herself.
When Ms. G made up her mind
about something.
there was no stopping her.
man. for real.
And after we raised
the money to bring her
to Long Beach.
there she was.
But. damn.
I didn't expect
her to be so small.
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
The bounty on a Jew
was about $2.
Someone desperate for money
told the Gestapo.
On August 4th.
they stormed into my office.
and a man pointed a gun at me
and said. "Not a sound.
"Not one word."
And then they went
straight upstairs
to the attic.
I felt so helpless.
I could hear Anne screaming.
objects being thrown around.
So. I ran back to my house.
I looked for an earring
or knick-knacks. you know.
anything I could
take back with me
to bribe them.
So I took this back with me.
all these things.
and the soldier
there took out his gun
and put it against my head.
You could be shot
for hiding a Jew
or go to a camp.
So. another soldier
recognized my accent.
He was Austrian. and so was I.
but I had been adopted
by a Dutch family.
So. he told the soldier
with the gun to let me go.
There isn't a day
that I don't remember
August 4th
and I think about Anne Frank.
Yes?
I've never had a hero before.
But you are my hero.
Oh. no.
No. no. young man. no.
I am not a hero. No.
I did what I had to do.
because it was
the right thing to do.
That is all.
You know.
we are all ordinary people.
But even an ordinary secretary
or a housewife or a teenager
can. within their
own small ways.
turn on a small light
in a dark room.
Ja?
I have read your letters.
and your teacher
has been telling me
many things
about your experiences.
You are the heroes.
You are heroes every day.
Your faces
are engraved in my heart.
You hungry?
You know
what you're gonna say
in that courtroom?
I know what I have to say.
Yeah.
You know how that is.
I know.
And that man
that put your father
in prison.
he knew he was sending
an innocent man.
But. you know.
he was just
protecting his own.
What the hell does everybody
want from me?
(DOG BARKING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Hey. Mama. Mama.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I want to come home.
I don't want to be
in the streets no more.
I'm sorry.
I want to change.
I can't do it alone.
I need you. Mama.
I need you.
And what time was that?
I told you. 9:00. 9:30.
And you had a clear view
of the defendant.
Grant Rice. in the store?
I told you he was playing
the video game.
Then what happened?
What did you see?
Well. he got all whacked
because he lost the game.
and then he started
shouting and all.
threatening everybody.
He threatened everyone?
He threatened you?
No. The guy
who ran the store.
He wanted his money back
for the game.
And what did the store owner do?
He shouted back.
And they were fighting.
Then he. the defendant.
knocked something over
and left the store.
And then what happened?
What did you see?
I saw...
Paco did it.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Paco killed the guy.
(MAN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(DOG BARKING)
(SHOUTS
IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
My father won't
talk to me anymore.
And I have to lay low
for a little while
because there's word out
to jump me.
So I'm gonna be
living with my aunt.
See. uh. my aunt lives
even further away.
so I was just wondering
if I could. like. uh.
stay here late with you
so I can get my homework done.
'cause it's late
by the time I get home.
You can stay
as late as you want.
And I can even drive you
to your aunt's.
if it gets too late.
(LAUGHS)
Ms. G. let's not get nuts.
I think I got your color.
♪ Stand for life.
stand for truth
♪ Stand for something
don't fall for nothing
♪ Stand for love.
stand for power
♪ Stand for something
don't fall for nothing
♪ Stand for me.
stand for you
♪ Stand for something
don't fall for nothing
♪ Don't fall for nothing
Just come by the concierge
on your way out.
I'll have
the directions for you.
Yep. that's fine.
♪ Stand for life
stand for truth
♪ Stand for something
don't fall for nothing ♪
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Stop!
That's it! Now. now! Hey!
You get an extra
three seconds. Go!
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
MAN: enraged them
and provoked them
into acts of violence.
BEN: In 1961. an interracial
civil rights group
traveled by bus
through the South
to challenge segregation.
Blacks sat in the front.
whites in the back.
They were attacked.
firebombed.
but they kept going.
In Montgomery.
Alabama. Jim Zwerg
offered to be
the first off the bus.
knowing there was a mob
waiting for them.
He was almost beaten to death
so the others could get away.
That kind of courage
is unbelievable to me.
I was afraid of just being
in this class.
and I was ashamed
because I've always been
the dumb kid in school.
even with my friends.
But not anymore.
And I must have
some kind of courage.
because I could have lied
to get out of here.
but I stayed.
I stayed.
Hi. I'm home!
Sorry. it got late.
I drove the kids home.
I didn't want them taking buses.
You're never gonna believe
what happened.
Oh. I'm so tired.
It's so cute. though.
They never want to go home.
We have such
a good time together.
I'm gonna take a shower.
If you have another glass.
you're gonna have a headache.
Your bags are packed
and you think the wine's
gonna give me a headache?
Why are you doing this?
Because I don't
pay enough attention to you?
No. That's not it.
I just...
I feel like I'm living a life
I just did not agree to.
Erin. it's just...
It's... It's too hard.
Your life is too hard?
I think what
you're doing is noble.
And it's good.
And I'm proud of you.
I am.
I just want to live my life
and not feel bad about it.
I'm not trying
to make you feel bad.
You don't have to try.
I didn't plan on becoming
responsible for these kids.
Well. who asked you to?
No one asked me to!
They're not even your kids!
Why do I have to be asked?
Scott...
I finally realized
what I'm supposed to be doing
and I love it.
When I'm helping these kids
make sense of their lives.
everything about my life
makes sense to me.
How often does
a person get that?
Then what do you need me for?
You're my husband.
Why can't you stand by me
and be part of it.
the way wives support husbands?
Because I can't be your wife.
I wish I could make that
sound less awful.
Erin?
You know. if you
had to choose between us
and the class.
who would you pick?
If you love me.
how could you
ever ask me that?
Erin. look at me.
This is all
there's ever been to me.
This is it.
I'm not one of those kids.
I don't have any more potential.
See? You don't want
to be here either.
'cause if you did.
would you be in the classroom
every night?
That's not true.
I want to be here.
I love you.
You love the idea of me.
But it's such a great idea.
I know.
(DIALING)
Dad? Hi.
You know.
I was actually trying
to call someone else.
and I automatically
dialed you. I'm sorry.
Look. um.
I'm gonna call you tomorrow.
okay?
I need to make this call.
I love you.
(GULL CAWING)
ANDRE: Ms. G made us read
12 Angry Men.
It's all about
how this one juror
helped to turn the hearts
of 11 jurors.
It made me feel hopeful.
At 2:00 today.
my brother was given
a verdict on his own trial.
No O.J. Dream Team.
just a court-appointed
attorney
who probably thought
his ass was guilty.
And I realized 12 Angry Men
was just a book
and nothing more.
My brother got 15 years to life.
Justice don't mean
the bad guy goes to jail.
It just means somebody
pays for the crime.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
So. you got time now?
Anyone know where Andre's been?
I haven't seen him on the bus.
JAMAL: Yeah. I haven't
talked to him either.
Ms. G?
Mmm-hmm.
Are we gonna have
this same room next year.
again?
I don't know.
You're gonna be
juniors next year.
What do you mean?
Well. I teach freshman
and sophomore years.
You mean.
we're not gonna be
with you next year?
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
Well. I...
I don't teach juniors.
I thought you guys
understood that.
BOY: What?
What are you talking about?
(ALL CHATTERING)
You don't wanna be
our teacher next year?
Of course I do. I can't.
BOY: Why not?
It's the Board of Ed.
It's regulations.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Ms. G hasn't been here
long enough
to have seniority.
BOY 2: Who cares
about seniority?
Shit! They can't do that!
They don't have the right!
Ms. G.
this is our kick-it spot.
ALL: Yeah.
Everybody's cool
with everybody.
Everybody knows everybody.
This is the only place
where we really
get to be ourselves.
There's no place like this
out there for us.
That's true.
I'm not allowed
to teach junior and seniors.
GIRL: You're not allowed?
Ms. G.
we can fight this. you know.
like the Freedom Riders.
Yeah. yeah.
we'll all drive around
on a bus.
Only this time.
they try and bust us up.
we bust a few of them
board members' heads.
Marcus.
Or we can go
to the newspapers.
media.
That'll get their attention.
Or we can paint
the administration building
with the word "assholes"
in various colors.
GIRL: Hey. it's something.
We can do this.
What?
These are my books.
not Scott's.
I'm packing the wrong books.
Honey. take a break.
Sit down.
I can't believe
I'm getting divorced.
I never thought
this would happen.
(SIGHING)
What do I do now?
Next year.
I won't even have my kids.
You think you should
stay with them?
Or is it better they move on?
I don't know.
It's just a job. like you said.
Yeah. it is.
But is the job finished?
Listen to me now.
What you've done
with those kids...
I don't even have words for it.
But one thing's for sure.
you are an amazing teacher.
Special.
You have been blessed
with a burden. my daughter.
And I envy you that.
And I admire you.
And how many fathers
ever get to say that
to their daughters
and really mean it?
MARGARET: What she
is suggesting is in violation
of our union charter.
She may not move on
with her students
to teach them junior year.
She's only been here two years.
There are teachers here
who have tenure.
who have worked
and committed themselves
for far longer
to attain a position
of seniority.
Not to mention their experience
in teaching students
of a higher caliber.
The Distinguished
Scholars Program
is under our jurisdiction.
I don't want to replace
the Distinguished
Scholars Program.
I just want to stay
with my kids next year.
She can't.
I have the juniors.
The Board of Education
will not allow this.
Teaching rotations
will be disrupted.
retirement schedules
will be reevaluated.
disrespecting teachers
who have earned
their way far longer
and who focus on the classroom.
not on public relations
and newspaper articles.
I didn't ask
for those articles
to be written.
She's in the middle
of a divorce.
Note. they stay late
in her class. they're eating.
they're playing games!
All right. let's all
just take a breath here.
All right?
Now I had hoped
that we could talk this out.
maybe come to some
kind of arrangement.
There is no arrangement...
Margaret.
Carl. look.
Putting aside
all obvious resentments
for the moment.
even if an arrangement were made
and she could
teach them as juniors.
there isn't an accredited course
in the curriculum
for her to teach.
Unless Brian trades
one of his junior classes
for a sophomore.
No.
Then there's nothing I can do.
So that's it?
Believe it or not.
Ms. Gruwell.
there are other
capable teachers
in this school.
If you've made the progress
you say you have.
your students
should be ready to move on.
They might even gain something
from more experienced teachers.
You can't teach them.
You don't even like them.
What does that have to do
with teaching?
I've been an educator
for over 30 years.
I have students that still
remain in touch with me.
I know what it is
to be loved by a classroom!
You have no idea
how many battles I've had
fighting to be a better teacher.
and now. what.
suddenly I'm incapable
of educating your students?
You know. if they move on
to our classes and they fail.
it'll be because
they weren't prepared!
It'll be because you failed.
not them!
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
Andre? Wait a minute
before you go in.
I heard about
your brother's conviction.
I'm sorry.
Is that why
you've missed class so much?
I had things to do.
About this.
The evaluation assignment
was to grade yourself
on the work you're doing.
You gave yourself an F.
What's that about?
It's what I feel
I deserve. That's all.
Oh. really?
You know what this is?
This is a "Fuck you" to me.
and everyone in this class!
I don't want excuses.
I know what you're up against.
We're all of us
up against something.
So you better make up your mind.
because until you have the balls
to look me straight in the eye
and tell me
this is all you deserve.
I am not letting you fail.
even if that means
coming to your house
every night
until you finish the work.
I see who you are.
Do you understand me?
I can see you.
And you are not failing.
So. take a minute.
Pull yourself together
and come inside.
I want a new evaluation.
An F. What. are you tripping?
I want you all to know
that Dr. Cohn and I
tried very hard.
But it's been decided
we can't continue
with each other junior year.
GIRL: What?
BOY: What?
(ALL CHATTERING)
You... Wait.
Wait. Guys. Everyone.
No! That don't fly. Ma!
Look. first of all.
I'm not anyone's mother
in here. okay?
No. it doesn't mean mother.
It's a sign of respect for you.
Listen to me.
All of you.
Don't use me
as another excuse
for why you can't make it.
You made it to your junior year.
Think about how you did that.
Everyone in this room
has a chance to graduate.
For some.
you'll be the first
in your family.
The first with a choice
to go to college.
Some may move
faster than others.
But you'll each have the chance.
And you did that. Not me.
Now. I have one
final project in mind.
BOY: Ms. G.
Yeah?
EVA: Ms. G wanted us
to put our diaries together
in a book. just like Anne Frank.
She got this businessman.
John Tu.
to donate 35 computers
so we could work.
She told us we have something
to say to people.
We weren't just kids
in a class anymore.
We were writers
with our own voices.
our own stories.
And even if nobody else read it.
the book would be something
to leave behind
that said we were here.
this is what happened.
we mattered.
Even if it was
just to each other.
And we won't forget.
Ms. G didn't promise
it would get published
or anything.
but we could get it
out there ourselves.
She asked us
to come up with a title.
something to call ourselves.
I just received a call
from Karin Polacheck
at the Board of Education.
There's to be
a meeting with Dr. Cohn
about your classes.
Do you know anything about this?
No.
These students. this class.
they've become a family.
To who? To you?
To each other.
Room 203 is a kind of
a home for them.
Their trust
is all wrapped up in us
being together as a group.
Once they're out of her class.
believe me they'll slip back
into their old habits.
Their reading scores.
their writing
has markedly improved.
Ms. Campbell.
On paper. But what
has she accomplished
in reality?
What about new students
that come in next year?
Can she repeat
this process every year?
Her methods are impractical.
impossible to implement
with regularity.
What if every teacher
performed in this way?
We have millions of children
to get through
the education system
in this country.
and we need a means
of accomplishing that
which allows as many students
to benefit as possible.
not just special cases.
And you honestly think
you can create
this family in every classroom.
for every grade.
for every student
you teach?
I don't know.
Thank you.
Hey. there go Ms. G.
Hey. there go Ms. G!
What happened?
So? Are we gonna be together
for junior year?
No.
What?
We're gonna be together
junior and senior year.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes!
(I HAVE A DREAM
BY COMMON PLAYING)
♪ I got a dream
we're gonna work it out
out out
♪ We're gonna
work it out out out
♪ We're gonna work it out
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ We're gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We're gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We're gonna work it out
out out
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ I'm gonna look
deep within myself
♪ I gotta find a way
♪ I have a dream
♪ My dream is to be free
My dream is to be
♪ My dream is to be
My dream is to be free
♪ In search of brighter days.
I ride through the maze
of the madness.
♪ Struggle is my address.
where pain and crack lives
♪ Gunshots comin' from sounds
of blackness
♪ Given this game
with no time to practice
♪ Born on the black list.
told I'm below average
♪ A life with no cabbage
♪ That's no money
if you from where I'm from
♪ Funny.
I just want some of your sun
♪ Dark clouds
seem to follow me
♪ Alcohol that my pops
swallowed bottled me
♪ No apology. I walk
with a boulder on my shoulder
♪ It's a Cold War
I'm a colder soldier.
♪ Hold the same fight
that made Martin Luther
the King
♪ I ain't usin' it
for the right thing
♪ In between lean
and the fiends.
hustle and the schemes
♪ I put together
pieces of a dream
♪ I still have one
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ I'm gonna look
deep within myself
♪ I gotta find a way
♪ I have a dream
♪ The world's seen me
lookin' in the mirror
♪ Images of me.
gettin' much clearer
♪ Dear self.
I wrote a letter
just to better my soul
♪ If I don't express it
then forever I'll hold.
inside
♪ I'm from a side
where we out of control
♪ Rap music in the 'hood
played a fatherly role
♪ My story's like yours.
yo it gotta be told
♪ Trying to make it
from a gangster
to a godlier role
♪ Read scrolls
that stowed slaves
♪ And Jewish people
in cold cage
♪ Hate has no color or age.
flip the page
♪ Now my rage
became freedom
♪ Writin' dreams in the dark.
they far but I can see 'em
♪ I believe in Heaven
more than Hell
♪ Blessings more than jail
♪ In the ghetto
let love prevail
♪ With a story to tell.
my eyes see the glory and well
♪ The world waitin' for me
to yell I have a dream
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ I have a dream
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
out out
♪ That one day
♪ We gonna work it out
♪ I have a dream
♪ I got a dream
♪ That one day
♪ I'm gonna look
deep within myself
♪ I gotta find a way
♪ I have a dream
♪ My dream is to be free
My dream is to be
♪ My dream is to be
My dream is to be free ♪
(IT'S R TIME
BY JEANNIE ORTEGA PLAYING)
♪ Oh. come on. Miami
♪ It's R time
Don't be shy. grab a guy and
♪ Go. move your body
♪ Show 'em how it goes down
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
♪ My time to step up
in this world
♪ This reggaeton with Jeannie
La candela let it burn
♪ So you could jump on this
Or you could stay with that
♪ But if you didn't know
by now
♪ Right here is where it's at
♪ So haters step aside
And watch how we gon' ride
♪ Ay. bendito
I'm sorry that you tired
♪ But I'm a do my thing
I'm gonna cross the line
♪ 'Cause we gon'
start this party
♪ And we gonna get it right
♪ Oh. come on. Miami
♪ It's R time
Don't be shy. grab a guy and
♪ Go
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
♪ Pa. you gon' be screaming
"Yo te quiero"
♪ And when you bop your head
to my flow
♪ This shit's so crazy
You gon' want more
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
♪ I keep it real with you
I'm not a diva
♪ So shake your ass
to this all night
♪ Oh. come on. Miami
♪ It's R time
Don't be shy. grab a guy and
♪ Go. move your body
♪ Show 'em how it goes down
When you're Latino
♪ Come on. Miami
♪ It's R time
Don't be shy. grab a guy and
♪ Go. move your body
♪ Show 'em how it goes down
(CHANGE
BY DARRIUS GARRETT PLAYING)
My moms kicked me out
when I got jumped into
the gang life.
I'd like her to see me graduate.
♪ Need to change
if you wanna make it
♪ Change for a better day
♪ You're gonna talk the talk
So walk the walk
♪ Come on
♪ Need to change
if you wanna make it
♪ Change for a better day
♪ Are you hearin' what I say?
♪ Never had much of a thing
Popped out when I was thirteen
♪ Got some pussy
Did a lot of things
♪ Never been so free
Last day of slavery
♪ Only thing promised to me
Was the penitentiary
♪ At the fork in the road
Which way do I turn?
♪ Lot of mistakes that I made
Plus the lessons I've learned
♪ New trials and tribulations
Barely kept my sanity
♪ I've been fighting
my whole life
♪ And that's what made
the man in me
♪ A young man
without a place to call home
♪ Living long
In these streets I roam
♪ Lay my pillow
near the flames
♪ Scalp burned to the brain
♪ Skip class. up fast
And never learned a thing
♪ You can try
to work around it
♪ But the problem remains
♪ A group of hungry teens
Trying to get in the game
♪ Used to be me
What can I say?
♪ Look at the man
in the mirror
♪ And it's time
to make a change
♪ Need to change. everbody
My moms kicked me out
when I got jumped into
the gang life.
I'd like her to see me graduate.
♪ Need to change. everybody
I'd like to be 18.
♪ Do you hear me crying?
I need to change
♪ Need to change. everybody
♪ Need to change
for a better day
♪ Loving came
Only thing
♪ To pull me through
to another day
♪ Need to change. everybody
♪ Need to change
for a better day
♪ Loving came
Only thing
♪ To pull me through
to another day
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org